原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视资讯
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
请登陆 yysub.net
翻 译     辰星晓Reginamoon    -小y
-你没事吧  -你知道得越少越好
- Is everything okay? - The less you know, the better.
《失落的秘符》前情提要
Previously on "The Lost Symbol..."
翻 译     哈里不是波特   DerbyNinja
翻 译     米糊   Caroline   冰岛豆腐
三年前  扎克里·所罗门被殴打致死
Three years ago, Zachary Solomon was beaten to death.
校 对     苏葵
所以  这之间有什么联系吗
So, what's the connection?
这就是你要去土耳其寻找的答案
That's what you're going to Turkey to find out.
我陪他走完了最后一程
I was there with him in the end.
时间轴    Caroline    爱说谎的孩子
迈拉克说得很清楚他想让我单独行动
Mal'akh made it very clear that he wants me doing this on my own.
-敬身心联结  -干杯
- To the mind-body connection. - Cheers.
后 期     MythCreator
总 监     苏葵
土耳其  伊斯坦布尔
想来点什么
我知道现在不是季节
但今天多么适合来一杯四风烘焙啊
非常感谢
一切都还满意吗
无比满意
索贾尼  土耳其那边怎样了
Sojani, how's Turkey?
咖啡很棒
Great coffee.
我马上给你发一份东西过去
And, I'm gonna be sending you something shortly.
和杀了扎克里·所罗门的那个人有关
It's about the guy that killed Zachary Solomon.
失落的秘符
第一季第四集
她之前还来了
She was just here.
她来这里帮助我  而我做的
She came here to help me, and the last thing
-最后一件事却是欺骗她  -别
- I ever did was lie to her. - No.
-我本该听你的  -小凯...
- I should have listened to you. - Kat...
我为什么就没听...
Why couldn't I just listen to...?
我们怎么可能知道他会这样做
We couldn't have known he'd do something like this.
我们知道  他警告过我们
We did know! He warned us.
天啊  我当时到底在想什么
God, what was I thinking?
你在想你的父亲
You were thinking about your father.
我的父亲
My father.
我们甚至不知道他是否还活着
We don't even know if he's still alive.
他还活着
He's alive.
我想这么相信  真的  但...
I want to believe that, I do. But...
但假如他不在了  那翠茜的死就毫无意义了
but if he's not, then Trish died for nothing,
而我们的所作所为不过是将更多人置于险境
and all we're doing is putting more people in danger.
我必须确定他是否还活着
I have to know if he's alive.
唯一确定的方式
The only way to know for sure,
就是我们找到尖顶石  满足迈拉克的要求
is for us to find the capstone and give Mal'akh what he wants.
不是"我们"
Not us.
是你
You.
我不会抛下你
I'm not leaving you.
你必须独自完成这件事
You have to do this alone,
你必须按照他的要求来
you have to do what he wants.
找出线索  并祈祷最后发现你是对的
Find the clues, and hope that in the end, you're right,
这个古代奥义只是个传说
and this ancient wisdom is just some myth.
-当然是的  -你看见那段录像了
- Of course it is. - You saw what was on that film.
我不知道我看到的是什么
I don't know what I saw.
是某种自然现象  或是剪辑的把戏...
A natural phenomenon, a trick of editing...
爸爸总是提起这些历史异象
Dad would always cite these historical anomalies:
古埃及人是如何
how did the ancient Egyptians
搬动几百吨重的石块并建造了金字塔
move hundred-ton stones and build pyramids?
哥伦布造访前的美洲部落切割坚硬的花岗岩
How did the pre-Columbian tribes cut solid granite
是如何做到比用现代激光还要准确
with more precision than a modern laser?
他觉得这些也许可以用
He thought that it could be explained
某种我们已经遗忘了的力量来解释
by some kind of power that we've forgotten.
如果他是对的呢
What if he was right?
如果那种力量落入了某些真正邪恶的人手中呢
What if that power reemerged in the hands of someone truly evil?
我不能留在你身边提醒你
I'm not going to be there to remind you,
但如果你的思想不够开放
but if your mind isn't open,
你就限制了自己所能感知和理解的东西
you are limiting what you can perceive, and understand.
比如...来自宇宙的答案吗
Like, answers from the universe?
我们需要一切所能得到的帮助
We need all the help we can get.
小凯
Kat.
你不能回家去
You can't go back to the house.
佐藤八成派了人盯着呢
Sato probably has people watching it.
正合我意
I'm counting on it.
所以说  这位老兄操控它们自杀了
So, this dude made them kill themselves.
-一整群鸟吗  -不  那不可能
- A whole flock of birds? - No, that would be impossible.
那是怎么回事  集体自杀吗
So, what then? Mass suicide?
鸟类真会这么做吗
I mean, can birds even do that?
这肯定是经过了剪辑
It's got to be some kind of trick photography.
如果我能找到剪辑痕迹...
If I can just find the edits...
这个符号在你看来有意义吗
Does this mean anything to you?
看着像是个三曲腿图
Looks like a Triskelion.
怎么了
Why?
他在抛尸翠茜的地方  画了这个符号
Where he left Trish, he drew that.
这个符号在不同文化中代表着不同的事物
It represents different things to different cultures.
凯尔特  异教徒  共济会
Celtics, pagans, Freemasons.
大部分情况下它代表一个轮回
Most often it represents a-a cycle:
出生  死亡  重生
birth, death, rebirth.
你又是这表情
You got that look.
电影公司会用形状序列作为边缘编码
Film companies use shape sequences as edge code
标示不同信息  比如日期或生产编号
to indicate different things like date or production number.
正方形  三角形  X  十字
Squares, triangles, X's, crosses,
但直到80年代  他们才开始用三联形状序列
but they didn't start using three-shape sequences until the '80s.
圆形不该出现在这
This circle shouldn't be here.
有扫描仪吗
That a scanner?
好了  找到了
Okay, here we are.
好  盖上
Boom, got that...
早在一战时  缩影技术就运用于
Microdots were used as early as World War I
飞鸽传送的小纸条中
in tiny notes sent by carrier pigeon.
他们可以把信息
They could hide information in something
藏在标点符号大小的东西里
as small as a punctuation mark.
一位带有46的建筑师  用轻巧的砖块修建桥梁
在以坦等待被雕琢的石头  最终重回母腹
最后  要小心八哥的呼唤  因为搜寻之人必将坠落
-就是这样  -天呐
- There it is. - What the...?
一位带有46的建筑师  用轻巧的砖块修建桥梁
在以坦等待被雕琢的石头  最终重回母腹
最后  要小心八哥的呼唤  因为搜寻之人必将坠落
"一位带有46的建筑师
"An architect with 46,
用轻巧的砖块修建桥梁"
builds a bridge of weightless bricks."
这是个谜语
It's a riddle.
太不可思议了
That's incredible.
索贾尼找到了阿勒吉迪监狱以前的狱警
Sojani found a former guard from Ag Gecidi prison,
他现在在伊斯坦布尔经营一家咖啡店
now runs a coffee shop in Istanbul.
-他给了她这个  -这是什么
- He gave her this. - What am I looking at?
扎克里·所罗门  三年前在监狱的照片
Zachary Solomon, three years ago at the prison.
而这也是现存照片里唯一一张
And this is one of the only known photos
拍到了这位叫萨米亚扎的囚犯
of a prisoner who went by the name of Samyaza.
眼熟吗
Look familiar?
情报显示他很可能是杀害扎克里的凶手
Intel points to him as Zachary's likely killer.
这意味着  他留下了这个...
Which means, he left this...
你应该很眼熟
which should look familiar.
如果照这么想  这个人
And when you consider that, this guy?
看起来很像...
Starts to look a lot like...
-这个人  -不可能
- ...this guy. - No way.
你觉得他远赴五千英里来杀这光这家人吗
You think he came 5,000 miles to finish off the family?
永远不要低估有上帝情节的人
Never underestimate a man with a God complex.
前门安全
Hey, coast is clear out front.
-你想出来了  -算是吧
- You got it? - I think so.
"一位带有46的建筑师
"An architect with 46,
用轻巧的砖块修建桥梁
"Builds a bridge of weightless bricks.
在以坦等待被雕琢的石头
"In Etam waits a stone once hewn,
最终重回母腹
"Returned at last to mother's womb.
最后  要小心八哥的呼唤
"Lastly, heed the Starling's call,
因为搜寻之人必将坠落"
for all who seek must also fall."
好吧  我更擅长数独
Yeah, I'm more of a sudoku guy.
我也不确定是不是这个意思
I'm not sure if I know what it means either.
-"石头"说得很明显了  -是啊
- The word "Stone" is pretty clear. - Right.
以坦在哪
Wh-Where's Etam?
有趣的是  在公元前9世纪
It's interesting-- in the 9th century BC,
它是犹大王国的城市
it was a city located in the Kingdom of Judah.
现在  它大概在伯利恒南部
In present day, I'd put it somewhere south of Bethlehem?
你瞧  我本来觉得该跟着你
See, I was thinking I'd come with you
完成尖顶石任务
on this capstone mission,
但以色列对我来说有点远
but Israel might be a little far for me.
是啊  谢谢你的好意
Yeah, I appreciate the offer,
但我最好还是自己去
but I think it's best if I go it alone.
等等  你也许需要保护
Hold up. You might need protection.
那谁来保护你  还有你妻子
And who's going to protect you? And your wife?
佐伊去她表姐家住了  所以...
Zoe went to stay at her cousin's, so...
我觉得这次我得自己去
I think I got to do this on my own.
好吧  等等
Okay. All right, hold on, hold on.
等等  等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
如果有麻烦
Any sign of trouble,
你一定要打电话给我
make sure you get to a phone and you call me.
-谢谢  -好吗
- Thank you. - Yeah?
-好  -好吧
- Yeah. - All right.
没事的
Oh, all right.
-好了  -去吧  你从后门出去
- Yeah. - Come on. I'll let you out the back.
什么叫你不知道这是什么
What do you mean you don't know what it is?
你什么都知道
You know everything.
这就是知识被历史遗忘时会产生的问题
Well, that's the problem when knowledge gets lost to history.
但人们对巨石阵众说纷纭
But people have theories about henges, okay?
有人觉得巨石阵是远古墓地
Some people think that a henge was an ancient burial site.
还有人说古代天文学家
Other people say that ancient astronomers
把巨石阵当成日晷  你知道日晷吗
would use a henge as a sundial-- you know sundials?
他们用它来敬奉太阳神  日神
And they'd use it to worship a solar deity, a sun god.
我不明白为什么扎克和妈妈不想看巨石阵
I don't get why Zach and Mommy didn't want to see this.
宝贝  不是所有人都像你这么有好奇心
Well, sweetie, not everyone's as curious as you are.
要一直保持下去
Always keep that.
你让我很好奇  你是我自己的小日规
You make me curious; you're my own little sundial.
你在哪  爸
Where are you, Dad?
你好  凯瑟琳
Hi, Katherine.
我是佐藤井上
I'm Inoue Sato.
我能单独在我父亲的房子里待一会儿吗
Can I have a few moments alone in my father's house?
你觉得那是好主意吗
Do you think that's such a good idea,
考虑到发生的所有这些事
considering everything that's happened?
你和罗伯特经历了很多
You and Robert have been through a lot.
我无法想象这些会多么让你震惊
I can't imagine what a shock this has all been.
你父亲  现在是你的助理研究员
Your father, now your research assistant.
-如果我能做点什么...  -我就想让我爸爸回来
- If there's anything I can do... - I just want my dad back.
-我也是  -真的
- Me, too. - Really?
因为以我来看  你一直
Because, as far as I can tell, you've been spending
不遗余力地追踪我们
all your time chasing us.
我是想保护你
I'm trying to protect you.
有一次就在罗斯福准备发表演讲前
Roosevelt was once shot in the chest
他胸部中了弹
right before giving a speech.
不过并未让他慌乱
Didn't faze him, though.
之后他进行了标志性的演说
And he went on to give an iconic performance.
他们应该试试用毒气
They should have tried poisonous gas.
出什么事了
Something happen?
孩子  我刚被中情局在小黑屋
Son, I've been locked up in a CIA bed-and-breakfast
关了48小时
for the last 48 hours.
看来他们也在追踪入口
Seems they're after the portal as well.
是你叫我来的  为什么
Look, you called me here. Why?
我破译了圣经上的希伯来文
I decoded the Hebrew from the Bible page.
它指引我们去了橡树山公墓
It led us to Oaken Hill Cemetery.
来了一个人  想放毒气熏我们
Guy showed up, tried to gas us;
我想可能是你们利维坦社的朋友
I thought it might be one of your Leviathan friends.
我们之中有些成员
Well, there are members within the group that, uh,
会采取极端手段去保护秘密
will go to extremes to protect the secret.
凯瑟琳怎么样  她还好吗
How's Katherine? Is she all right?
不算太好
Not really.
她的一位女同事昨晚被杀了
A woman she works with was killed last night,
尸体被扔在了亚当斯纪念医院来警告我们
body was left at the Adams Memorial as a warning to us.
我听说了
I heard about that.
没想到和这件事还有关联
I had no idea there was a connection.
为了让我继续找  一个精神变态
A psychopath is killing people to ensure
在到处杀人  而你利维坦社的朋友们
that I keep going, and your Leviathan friends
戴着防毒面具过来  想要阻止我
are showing up in gas masks trying to get me to stop.
但如果我想让彼得回来的话  我就不能停止
But I can't stop, not if I want to get Peter back.
我能干什么
How can I help?
我们发现了一卷胶片
We found a film.
胶片边缘编码上隐藏着一个谜语  一条线索
There was a riddle hidden in the edge code, a clue:
"一位带有46的建筑师"
"An architect with 46."
其中6的首字母S写成了美元符号$
The "S" of the six written as a dollar sign.
46...
Forty-six...
-这数字对你有什么意义吗  -如果要猜的话
- That mean something to you? - Well, if I were to guess,
我会说那是指规划设计了
I'd say that was in reference to the architect
华盛顿哥伦比亚特区的建筑师
who designed the plans for Washington, D.C.
皮埃尔·查尔斯·朗方  他的确是共济会员
Pierre Charles L'Enfant. Who was a Mason,
这地方对得上  但为什么是"46"
so that part fits, but, uh, why "46"?
还有  这与尖顶石有什么关系
And-and, what does that have to do with the capstone?
有件事我不能告诉你
Well, that's something I can't tell you.
因为你害怕谁会发现吗
Because you're afraid of who might find out?
因为最好是带你去看
Because it would be better to show you.
我猜你会来这
Figured you'd come here.
实际上我就指望你会来呢
I was banking on it, actually.
是吗
Okay.
我需要个东西  只有中情局能提供
I need something only the CIA can provide.
你熟悉触物占卜术吗
Are you familiar with psychometry?
有时人能从个人物品中感知一些情况
Sometimes people can sense things off of personal objects,
感知到物品主人的一些情况
feel things about the people the objects belong to.
某种通灵探查
Kind of a psychic surveillance.
但有些人不需要物品
But some people don't need objects.
中情局把他们称为"千里眼"
The CIA refers to them as "Remote viewers."
并非我的专长
Not exactly my department.
但你知道星门计划
But you know about Project Stargate.
我知道该项目于1995年被终止了
I know it was terminated in 1995.
正式的说法是"终止官方资助"
"Officially defunded" was the technical designation.
一个附属的项目仍然存在
A side program still exists.
假设说  千里眼项目
If the remote viewing program
真的还在进行
were still active, hypothetically,
你为什么感兴趣
what's your interest?
我想和千里眼的头儿谈谈
I want to talk to the head viewer.
我需要他找到我父亲
I need him to find my father.
我尽力而为
I'll see what I can do.
同时  我今天收到了一些
In the meantime, I received some information today
你也许感兴趣的信息
that you might be interested in.
是关于我爸的吗
About my dad?
关于可能绑架他的人
About the man who might have taken him.
他的真名无人知晓
His real name is a mystery.
大部分人事档案在暴乱中烧毁了
Most of the personnel records were burned up in the riot,
但在监狱里  他叫萨米亚扎
but at the prison, he was called Samyaza.
这是什么名字
What kind of a name is that?
源自《圣经》  一位堕落天使
Biblical. A fallen angel.
据说  他完全融入了这个角色
By all accounts, this guy embraced the role.
在监狱里他是一个极端暴力犯罪团伙的头目
Ran an extremely violent drug gang at the prison,
激励奴隶般的忠诚
inspired slavish devotion.
不效忠的人就会被他打死
And those who wouldn't devote, he'd break.
我想扎克里就是其中一人
I think Zachary was one of those people.
一点也不出奇
That makes sense.
我哥哥反对正流派
My brother was pretty antiestablishment,
所以他不会加入邪教
so he wasn't about to join some cult.
不管他有什么问题
Whatever his issues, I think,
我认为扎克里想以自己的方式拨乱反正
in his own way, Zachary was trying to do the right thing.
这和我爸有什么关系
What does this have to do with my dad?
我想可能是同一个人
I think it might be the same guy.
什么
What?
先是你哥哥  然后是你父亲
First your brother, then your father.
-下一个有可能是你  -太扯了
- You could be next. - This is crazy.
扎克提过监狱里有这么一个人吗
Did Zach ever mention anyone like this at the prison?
我不...不知道  我不记得了  他...
I just don't-- I don't know, not that I can remember. He...
他给我写了几封信
He wrote me some letters.
信里可能提到过
There might be something in them.
我好多年没看了
I haven't looked at them in years.
如果可以的话  我想看看
I'd like to take a look, if that's okay.
我在星门计划的联络人刚刚联系我了
My contact at Project Stargate came through.
他找到你要找的人了  现在怎么做
He found the man you asked for. What now?
带他去我的实验室
Bring him to my lab.
然后你就可以看信了
Then you can have the letters.
事出紧急
It's urgent.
血压骤降  呼吸微弱
Blood pressure's plunging, respiration is weak.
-我可以稳定他的情况  -不需要
- I can stabilize him. - No need.
我们继续
We'll continue as is.
他有可能会死
He could die.
如果他要达成最终目的
He must go all the way through the process
他就必须完成整个过程
if he's to serve his ultimate purpose.
朗方本来身处世界之巅  然后一夜之间
L'Enfant was on top of the world; then, overnight:
被勒令离境
persona non grata.
有人说他想学得太多
Some say he tried to learn too much.
他只留下了三只表
All he left behind were three watches,
三个指南针  两本书和一张地图
three compasses, two books and a map.
他在人世间最后的随身物品
The last of his earthly possessions.
当时价值为46美元
Value at the time: $46.
看看书
Take the books.
《关于圣礼的迷信论述》
3点40分
3:40,
2点30分
2:30,
4点45分
4:45.
谜语为什么带我们找到这些
Why did the riddle lead to this?
多尔切斯特
伍斯特
萨默塞特郡
多尔切斯特
伍斯特
萨默塞特郡
奇怪
Weird.
纬度38的标记是蓝色墨水
The 38 latitude marker is in blue ink,
这在十九世纪早期
which would have been extremely expensive
价格非常昂贵
in the early 19th century.
Thirty-eight.
英国多尔切斯特
伍斯特
萨默塞特郡
看看第一只表  三和八
Look at that first watch: three and eight.
这不对
This isn't right.
如果这只表停在3点40分
If this watch had stopped at 3:40,
那么时针
then the hour hand would be
应该在三到四之间的三分之二位置
two-thirds of the way between three and four,
但两根指针都指向数字  这两只表也是
but both hands point precisely at numbers-- same for these two.
三和八  38
Three and eight: 38.
角度  分  秒
Degrees. Minutes. Seconds.
-三只表是坐标  -尖顶石的坐标
- These watches are coordinates. - Coordinates for the capstone.
-有可能  -难道不需要经度吗
- Could be. - Wouldn't you need longitude?
需要
Yes.
好吧  在哪呢
Okay, where are you?
你觉得这像什么
What does that look like to you?
共济会正方形
It's a Masonic square.
正方形代表了道德
The square represents morality.
而圆规
And the compass:
代表边界
boundaries.
这给了我们一个非常熟悉的符号
Which gives us a very familiar symbol.
"追求智慧之人
"Ye who are engaged in the pursuit of wisdom
必会使用规矩"
must also make use of the square and compass."
还有另一个
And the other.
所以...
So...
如果38度角  加上26分59秒
if 38 degrees, 26 minutes and 59 seconds
能给我们一条纬度线
gives us our latitude line,
然么圆规
then the compasses
就指向了经度
point to our longitude.
X代表交汇地点
"X" Marks the spot.
阿奎亚
-阿奎亚  -是斯塔福德县的一个小镇
- Aquia. - It's a town in Stafford County.
威京顿  那是朗方在阿奎亚买的采石场
Wigginton, that's a quarry in Aquia that L'Enfant purchased.
-采石场  -事实上  那座采石场
- A quarry. - In fact, half the buildings
为这里一半的建筑提供了砂岩
are made with sandstone from that quarry.
国会大厦  白宫
The Capitol Building, the White House,
华盛顿纪念碑...
the Washington Monument...
"在以坦等待被雕琢的石头
"In Etam waits a stone once hewn,
最终重回母腹"
returned at last to mother's womb."
尖顶石回到了
The capstone is returned
阿奎亚
它来自的采石场
to the quarry it came from.
凯瑟琳·所罗门
Katherine Solomon,
这是阿里欧·法兹利
meet Ario Fazeli.
非常感谢你能来
Thank you so much for coming.
阿里欧一开始为德黑兰的中情局工作
Ario started at the Agency in Tehran,
协助远程追踪被绑架的人质
helping to remotely track victims during the hostage crisis.
-他现在协助...  -米德堡基地  我知道你是谁
- Now, he assists at... - Fort Meade. I know who you are,
法兹利先生  我很荣幸
Mr. Fazeli. It's a pleasure.
你知道他在海底找到了泰坦尼克号吗
Did you know he located the "Titanic" on the ocean floor?
当然  他们不能把这放进电影里
They couldn't put it in the movie, of course.
国家安全之类的原因
National security or whatever.
我很荣幸你能来这里
Well, I'm just very glad you're here.
我们开始吧
Shall we get started?
"一位带有46的建筑师
"An architect with 46,
用轻巧的砖块修建桥梁"
builds a bridge of weightless bricks."
"在以坦等待被雕琢的石头
"In Etam waits a stone once hewn,
"最终重回母...
"Returned at last to mother's...
腹"
...womb."
你好  兰斯  兰斯  我在听
Yeah, hello? Lace, Lace, I'm here.
你有发现了  在清洁工身上  对吗
You got something? On the Janitor, right?
尼古拉斯·巴斯庭  你有地址吗
Nicholas Bastin. You got an address?
佩里街  挨着勒杜瓦公园那个吗
Perry Street. Yeah, up by LeDroit Park?
尼古拉斯·巴斯庭
佩里街8557号
你好  女士  我是阿方索·努奈兹
Hello, ma'am, my name is Alfonso Nuñez.
你也是中情局的吗  我已经跟他们谈过了
Are you with the CIA? 'Cause I already talked to them.
从没想过我会说出这种话
Never thought I'd hear those words come out of my mouth.
我不是  我来找尼古拉斯·巴斯庭
I'm not with them. I'm looking for Nicholas Bastin.
他们也是
So are they.
但他们不肯说找他做什么
They wouldn't tell me what they wanted with him, though.
你呢
Will you?
什么原因
What is it?
发生了什么
What happened?
你丈夫开枪打了我  而我想问问他为什么
Your husband shot me, and I'd like to ask him why.
但既然我不能  我就来找你了
But since I can't, I'm here talking to you.
他不再是我的丈夫了
He's not my husband anymore.
谢谢
Thank you.
你上一次见他是什么时候
When's, um, last time you saw him?
我不记得了  6或者7周前
I don't know, six or seven months?
不介意我问的话  你们在一起多久了
If you don't mind me asking, how long were you together?
6年  在他被派遣前
Six years, before he got deployed.
他是名军医
He was a medic.
想回来做名外科医生
Wanted to come back and become a surgeon,
但他回来后  情况就不一样了
but when he got back, things were different.
我也去了战场...
I was there, too, uh...
对婚姻来说这并不容易
It's tough on a marriage.
我们试着一起生活
We tried to start a family.
但我们没有缘分
But it wasn't meant to be.
然后他就回到中东旅行  逃避
Then he went back to the Middle East to travel, to get away.
说自己被那个地方吸引了
Said he felt drawn to that part of the world.
然后他遇到了一个人  什么大师
And he met someone, some guru.
说大师拯救了他
Said he saved his life.
这位大师有名字吗
Did this guru have a name?
尼克从没说过
Nick never said it.
仿佛那名字很神圣
Like it was sacred or something.
你看见过他  他看上去像"被拯救"了吗
You've seen him since-- did he seem "saved"?
我得走了
Um, I-I've got to go.
我有工作
I have work.
好的  我也得走了
Yeah, I got to go, too.
信仰联合医疗中心
我就是在信仰联合医院接受了治疗
I was, uh, treated at Faiths United.
-你是护士还是...  -药剂师
- You a nurse or... - Pharmacist.
我真的该走了
And I really got to go.
再次谢谢你的时间
Thanks again for your time.
意念科学最基本的信念就是
A fundamental belief of noetic science is that
一切信息都有超越时空的联系
all information is connected beyond space and time:
预感  直觉
hunches, intuition,
甚至在某人打电话前就知道他们要打来
even knowing when someone is about to call right before they do.
我是科学家  所以我首先要承认
I'm a scientist, so I'm the first to admit
这类事情有大范围的误差
that there is a wide margin of error here.
但是我需要尝试
But I need to try.
我所知的千里眼
From what I know about remote viewing,
是地点导向
it's location-directed.
他不需要坐标吗
He doesn't need coordinates?
那是传统模式
That's the traditional model.
在这个模式里  彼得本身就是地点
In this model, Peter himself is the location,
阿里欧要试着看见他  或见他所见
and Ario is trying to see him, or see what he sees.
可能会是颜色  气味  味道的闪现
It could come in flashes of color, smells, tastes,
视觉影像转瞬即逝
visual images so fleeting,
未经训练的大脑可能会抓不住
a less-trained mind might miss them.
我要在6点打匹克球
I have pickleball at 6:00.
从美国西雅图的本不里奇岛兴起
网球  羽毛球和乒乓球的混合运动
好  你准备好就开始
Of course. Whenever you're ready.
太蠢了
So stupid.
"最后  要小心八哥的呼唤"
"Lastly, heed the Starling's call,
"因为搜寻之人必将坠落"
for all who seek must also fall."
再说一次  目标的名字是彼得·所罗门
Again, the name of the target is Peter Solomon.
出生于1963年  哈佛校友
Born in 1963, alumnus of Harvard,
史密森学会的书记员
secretary of the Smithsonian.
我的父亲
My father.
有...一定程度的强度
There's... a degree of intensity.
-一种与生物相关的强度  -人类还是动物
- Something biological. - Human or animal?
有一个规矩的图形
There's an upright point.
一个三角形  一个长方形
A triangle, a rectangle.
一种金属质感的味道  一种永久的味道
A... a metallic taste, something permanent.
有某样很白  或者是反射了灯光的事物
Ah, something very white, or that reflects light.
一个承载着水的环境
Some element containing water.
冷  冷
Cold, cold.
非常冷
I-It's cold.
焦虑
T-Tension.
有东西在变慢
There's slowing, it's...
在变暗
darkening.
诞生
死亡
重生
抱歉  看不见了
I'm sorry, it's gone.
发生什么了  你看见了什么
What happened? What did you see?
都在这了  只是  我...
It's all here. It's just that I, um...
我感应到他了  然后...
I sensed him, and then...
我觉得他已经死了
I don't think he's with us anymore.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
这类事情有大范围的误差  你说的
There's a wide margin of error, you said that.
这些不代表什么
This doesn't mean anything.
抱歉  我需要去透一下气
I'm sorry, I need some air.
你真的看到他了
Did you really see him?
我感应到他了
I sensed him.
牛津大学给我提供了研究员的位置
I got offered a fellowship at Oxford.
恭喜  这太棒了
Well, congratulations, that's great.
谢谢  我不知道该怎么办
Thank you. I don't know what to do.
去牛津会让我在最糟糕的时候离开凯瑟琳
It'd take me away from Katherine at the worst possible time,
还有你
as well as you, too.
我从各个角度分析过了
I've analyzed it from every angle,
考虑了各种变量  各种可能的结果
all the variables, possible outcomes...
好  好
Yeah. Yeah.
可你不能像解决谜题一样解决这个  罗伯特
Well, you can't solve this like one of your puzzles, Robert.
这不一样  这是人生
This is different, this is life.
那我该怎么决定
How do I decide then?
用你的直觉
Use your intuition.
"对有信仰之人来说  不需要任何理由
"To one of faith, no explanation is needed.
对无信仰之人来说  没有理由能说得通"
To one of no faith, no explanation is possible."
托马斯·阿奎奈[意大利神学家]
Thomas Aquinas.
你知道我不相信神
You know I don't believe in a higher power.
你从没经历过
I mean, have you never experienced
你无法解释的事情吗
something you couldn't explain?
你从来没想过  哪怕就那么一刻
Have you never considered, even for a moment,
或许有更大的力量在操纵人世
there might be something larger at work?
我8岁的时候  我离家出走
When I was eight years old, I ran away from home.
我只记得想要离开  躲起来
I just remember wanting to get away, hide.
林子里有一口老井
And there was this, uh, old well in the woods.
我降下去了大约一半的距离
I lowered myself about halfway down,
然后没抓稳掉了下去  救命
and I lost my grip and fell. Help!
发生了什么
So what happened?
我试图爬上去  但井壁太湿了
I tried to get back up; the walls were too wet.
我困住了  不停踩水
I was stuck, treading water.
我大声呼救  但没人来
I yelled for help, but no one came.
救命  来人啊
Help! Someone!
好像过了数小时
It seemed like hours.
我本来都想放弃了  让自己沉下去
I was going to give up, let myself drown.
然后我...
And then I...
我听到一个声音  好像就在我身边
I heard this voice, like it was right there with me.
它让我继续呼救  继续呼救
It told me to keep going. Keep going.
它说他们会找到我
It said that they'd find me.
然后他们找到了你
And they found you.
你觉得那是什么
What did you think it was?
我当时精疲力尽  神志不清
I was exhausted, delirious.
是我的大脑在捉弄我
It was my mind playing tricks.
也许是时候停止坚持认为
Well, maybe it's time to stop insisting that
那个声音不真实  并尝试再次倾听它
that voice wasn't real, and try listening for it again.
当然会有个洞穴等着我了
And then it had to be a cave.
好的
All right.
"奥秘隐藏于秩序之中"
"The secret hides within The Order."
抓住我的手
Take my hand!
抓到你了
Gotcha.
用力
Come on.
看来单干效果不是很好
Guess going solo didn't exactly pan out.
-你是怎么...  -在你外套里放了个追踪器
- How did you...? - Put a tracker in your coat.
不久前信号断了
Signal went dead a little while ago.
感觉可能发生了不好的事
Had this feeling something bad might've happened,
所以我跟着它走  走到了这里
so I followed it and it led me here.
-你在我身上放了追踪器  -是的
- You put a tracker on me? - Yeah.
是在拥抱我时放的  对吗
It was the hug, wasn't it?
确实是
It was the hug.
土耳其  于斯屈达尔
凯瑟琳·所罗门
...他好的一面
我打算低调点
....不让他生气
不想被注意到
内部军阀
获利
很多谣言
一个先知  一个医者
他们说他有"神力"
星门计划
Project Stargate?
我听说你从子项目里找了一个
I hear you pulled some guy named Ario Fazeli
叫阿里欧·法兹利的人
out of the sub-program.
你的任务是找到罗伯特·兰登
Your job is to find Robert Langdon,
而不是跟她女友举办降神会  到底什么情况
not hold a séance with his girlfriend; so what's going on?
我在接近凯瑟琳  这样当兰登出现时
I'm getting close to Katherine, so that when Langdon surfaces,
我会等着他
I'm right there waiting.
就像你想在他找到你的入口时等着  对吧
Just like you want to be when he finds your portal, right?
你选择了我是因为我总能完成任务
You chose me because I always get it done,
所以就交给我办
so let me do it.
随时给我汇报
Keep me apprised.
我说不好
I don't know about this, man.
她说她不想见你
She said she doesn't want to see you.
-她害怕了  -是啊  她应该害怕
- She's afraid. - Yeah, she should be.
她就在那
There she is.
我只是觉得她会想要看到这个
I just think she'd really want to see this.
是啊  迈拉克肯定也想
Yeah, I bet Mal'akh would, too.
听着  我的意思是
Look, all I'm saying is, is
在我为了拯救你而经历的一切之后
after everything I done been through to save your ass,
我可不想因为你忍不住
I'm not gonna have you get carved up
想向女友邀功而被人开肠破肚
'cause you can't keep your puzzle in your pants.
我只是说说而已
I'm just saying.
我今天在那边的时候  几乎好像
When I was out there today, it was almost like,
有那么一刻  我也不知道
for a moment, I don't know,
仿佛彼得就在我身边一样
Peter was right there with me.
所以你才想见她
That's why you want to see her.
告诉她你现在相信神灵了
Tell her you believe in stuff now.
也许我只是想让她知道
Maybe I just want her to know.
开车吧
Drive.
好
Yup.
恭喜毕业
你的时代到来了
我的日晷
爱你的爸爸
我不会放弃的  爸爸
I won't give up, Dad.
凯蒂
Katie...
保存你的体力
Save your strength.
你之后会需要
You're going to need it.